Previously on
Star Trek Strange New Worlds...
I am calling to let you know
that we have chosen
not to offer you a fellowship.
I've been trying to tell you
I just need some personal time.
I am having difficulty
watching you experience
such obvious distress.
I want to help. But it would appear
all that I'm doing is making it worse.
- James?
- You two know each other?
I have to insist
that you not share
any of what you experienced
from this time.
Those events
were never supposed to happen.
and you were never meant to be
aware of them.
Neither was your companion.
I was wrong.
I don't deserve you.
But I'm asking. Will you forgive me?
Communication Officer's Log.
Stardate 2398.3.
Traveling in the far edges
of the Alpha Quadrant.
we have encountered
an unusual phenomenon...
A naturally-occurring subspace fold.
Lieutenant Spock posits
it could be used to
triple the speed of
subspace communications in the sector.
But his experiment requires
so much computer power
that the rest of the ship
has to communicate...
Hailing frequencies open.
...the old-fashioned way.
On it.
I'll route that right to you.
Pike to Uhura.
Have you hailed Captain Batel?
Hailing now. Captain.
I'll send her to your quarters
when I have her.
Transporter to Uhura.
Has the U.S.S. Farragut confirmed
Lieutenant James Kirk's arrival?
Checking on that now. Commander.
Medical to Uhura.
Is there a message from Dr. Korby yet?
Just arrived. Stand by.
Engineering to Uhura.
Are you ready to continue
our experiment?
Yes. Lieutenant. momentarily.
You want to go to Crivo
for our first vacation together?
- I know it's cliché...
- And touristy.
Chris. I have always wanted to see
the Crivian Planetary Museum.
and there are day trips
to the Glass Islands
and Smoke Lakes.
I know you love a lake.
What's wrong?
Uh. maybe the timing is bad.
I-I'm just not sure
I can get away right now.
Is there something
you're not telling me. Chris?
Of course not. No. Uh...
But let's just put a pin on planning
for a few days?
Whenever you want. I'll be here.
Lieutenant Kirk's captain
sent a report
in advance of his arrival.
"Show him the ropes.
"Kirk's full of talent.
but still has one or two issues
"to work out
before he begins his commission."
Yeah. Punctuality being one.
You have...
An energy.
What? I'm just waiting
for our visitor to arrive.
so I can run
a security clearance on him.
I'm aware. but you came in here hot.
On fire. It's making me sweat.
I-I'm fine. This is just
standard operating procedure.
Lieutenant Kirk!
Welcome back to the Enterprise.
Thank you. Commander.
No Sam? Thought he'd be here.
He's busy. We'll find him later.
Thank you for agreeing to do this.
even if it's not fully necessary.
When I took my commission.
I spent a week shadowing Pike.
It made all the difference.
Hopefully it'll do the same for you
on the Farragut.
Good to see you again. La'An.
You still owe me that drink.
if I'm not mistaken.
You... know each other?
Um...
Ye-Yes. but I still need to do
a security clearance.
Lead the way.
Oh. sorry. I...
And what if it's another rejection?
Forget those Vulcans
and their science academy.
They don't deserve you.
Ah. but this fellowship is different.
Dr. Korby's a genius.
Am I supposed to know
who that is?
He's the Louis Pasteur
of archaeological medicine.
Yeah. no. Still means nothing.
It means that thousands of people
apply for this fellowship every year.
and only five are accepted.
This could change my life.
Okay.
Oh... Oof.
You got it. I knew it.
What will I do without you
for three months?
Oh. my God.
You're not the only one
who's gonna miss her.
Oh. I have to talk to Spock.
Unfortunately. we have had
another communication failure.
That's our 12th attempt
at sending a message
through the subspace fold.
13!
That's not exactly what I would call
a lucky number.
What makes you think that
this particular fold
will lead to faster communication?
Frequencies propagate through it
three times faster than normal.
- Ah.
- With our current relay network.
it takes weeks to send a message
across the quadrant.
Imagine being able to do it in moments
and getting a near-instant reply.
Real-time communication
across thousands of light years.
Only. so far. no one's heard us.
Have you tried sending music through?
We have not.
Do you believe music may yield
a different result?
Well. you are trying to communicate
through a medium
with different laws of physics.
so. perhaps. fundamental harmonics
are the answer. Hmm?
You know. it was just a thought.
But perhaps an excellent one.
You pick the song. Nyota.
Well. let's see if subspace is a fan
of the Great American Songbook. huh?
In olden days
A glimpse of stocking
Was looked on as something shocking
But now. God knows
Anything goes
Good authors too
Who once knew better words
Now only use four-letter words
Writing prose
Anything goes
Mitchell. what just hit us?
No other ships in this sector. sir.
It looks like it came
from that subspace fold.
Ensign Uhura.
are you patched into comms?
Aye. sir.
I need a full status report.
All stations.
Apologies.
Reporting from Engineering first. sir.
Mr. Spock?
The intermix chamber
and containment field are stable
I'll get to the warp core
And assess its state
When I'm able
Why?
Where's that music coming from?
Not from anywhere on the ship.
Apologies
The most confounding thing
I appear to be singing
I have sickbay for you. sir.
Most unusual. so peculiar
We can confirm
There are no injuries
Just the daily mundane
A headache. a splinter
A left ankle sprain
It's happening again
Why are we singing?
Apologies
The most confounding thing
We appear to be singing
Most unusual. so peculiar
Lieutenant Ortegas. status report.
Ortegas is at the helm
The pilot seat is my realm
We're in a field. surrounded
Still. flight systems steady
Impulse engines ready
At the console
Systems initializing
Life support robust. now finalizing
We'll check inertial dampers
And see if they're hampered
All is okay
It appears that all is okay
Security detects no threats
We'll do a personnel overhaul
No decks unchecked
All tactical functions are steady
Phaser banks. deflector shields
All at the ready
Apologies
The most confounding thing
We appear to be singing
Most unusual. so peculiar
Apologies
The most confounding thing
So peculiar
All systems stable
- All systems stable
But why are we singing?
Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission.
to explore strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations.
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
So... that happened.
Reports of musical outbreaks
have come in from every deck.
Honestly. I assumed it was something
you had all rehearsed.
but I sang. too.
So did I.
And I do not sing.
The surge came from
your subspace fold.
Help me connect the dots.
We sent
a series of transmissions through.
The final one was a song.
You sent in a song.
and then we all... sang?
Why are we singing?
I believe the song created
a resonant frequency
and dislodged something from the fold.
a quantum uncertainty field.
Okay. why would that make us sing?
Imagine an area of space
where quantum uncertainties collapse
so rapidly and randomly
that new realities are created.
In one such reality.
people sing uncontrollably.
A musical reality.
Indeed.
So. what's next?
More improbability?
Or will we just
suddenly poof into bunnies?
I would prefer not to be
a bunny. either.
I doubt we will be bunnies.
but we may not be done with singing.
Simulations reveal
we have become tethered to
this particular improbability field.
Attempting to fly out
would likely make it wider.
It looks like a zipper.
which begs the question.
might it function like a zipper?
Zippers work both ways.
Could we use it to close
the improbability field
back inside the fold?
Potentially.
If we combined shield harmonics
with the Heisenberg compensator.
You would have to connect both to
the deflector array
and generate a beam.
That means connecting them manually.
Let's do it.
We don't know
how all this singing will affect us.
and I'd rather not find out.
Best to nip it in the bud.
Mr. Spock.
you explained that very well.
I almost understood it.
Our zipper beam must precisely
match the resonance of the fold.
What was the exact frequency
of the song we sent through?
One moment.
Is that transmission
regarding Nurse Chapel's
recent fellowship application?
Was the news... favorable?
I don't look at
personal correspondence.
Of course. That would be unethical.
You and Nurse Chapel
have become close. haven't you?
I suppose
it would be accurate to say that
we are more than colleagues.
There's that classic Vulcan romance
I've heard about.
Why don't you ask her about it?
Of late. our communication
has faced challenges.
Mmm.
Number One to Uhura.
Lieutenant Kirk and I are in place.
Stand by for harmonics data.
One junction down.
Only four more to go.
Don't tell me
you've run out of steam already.
You know. my brother.
he always described you as
"the first officer
that I thought I should be like."
Someone who keeps
a necessary distance from her crew
because she knows
she has to make hard decisions.
I'm aware of the reputation
I've had on this ship.
but recently.
I'm trying a new approach.
More hands-on.
My last first officer
definitely kept his distance.
And no one questioned him.
I call that style of command
a first mistake.
The kind that makes my head shake
and my heart... break.
Take some advice
From your senior Number One
This I assure tried and true
The littlest things
Can mean everything
When it comes to them and you
Connect to your crew
We're singing again
And it makes me confess things
I'd never express
Truth be told. in a parallel world
I can see myself up on the stage
And for three hours a night
And to everyone's delight
I'd regale them
With all my renditions
Of Gilbert and Sullivan
- Ha-ha.
- So what you're saying is...
With my new commission
To a higher position
I'd do well to profess my truths?
Rather than question it
I deem it relevant
No longer will I dispute
That the littlest things
Can mean everything
In being authentically you
Connect to your truth
When you put it like that.
it makes sense.
Rather than question it
Let's deem it relevant
Absent from fear or dispute
These deeply held things
Yes. they mean everything
In becoming authentically you
Connect to your truth
And connect to your crew
Will do
Did I hear that right?
Did she just shine a spotlight
On her innermost feelings
Like it's no big deal?
Say whatever whenever you like
You'd presume with all my mastery
To pursue flights of fancy
Easy.
Who am I kidding?
I've never found that part of me
'Cause I'm designed
To color inside the lines
Cool and methodical
Way too responsible
I can't help it
Sometimes I peek through a keyhole
And see people happy. I admit
It might
Be time to change my paradigm
If only I
Can let go of the wheel
My fear replaced with total faith
I'm fiercely free and really real
Flying blind
How would that feel?
This all makes me so uncomfortable
I want to let go. be vulnerable
Who am I kidding?
I've never met that side of me
In my defense
The truth has a consequence
I won't watch the whole thing
Spin out of control
If I have the chance
It might
Be time to change my paradigm
If I
Can only let go of the wheel
My fear replaced with total faith
I'm fiercely free and really real
Flying blind
How would that feel?
In another time
We had a life together
Could time repeat?
Or will it unravel?
Be careful what you start
Make one mistake
And blow it all apart
Or worse
Break my own heart
Who am I kidding?
I've never found that part of me
It might
Be time to change my paradigm
If only I
Can let go of the wheel
It's nice
To dream that I could change my mind
Deep down I know
I will never let go
My fear is staked
I have no faith
Contented freedom is not real
Flying blind
How would that feel?
When people sing.
they are confessing highly personal...
emotional information.
Lieutenant. are you telling me
our emotions constitute
a security threat?
I am.
Well. whatever you're not saying.
hope it doesn't come to that.
Mr. Spock and Ensign Uhura
have a plan to shut it down.
Captain. we have adjusted
the Heisenberg compensator
to combine with shield harmonics
and collapse the musical reality
back into our standard quantum state.
Lieutenant Kirk. not to rush you.
but I'm rushing you.
The sooner we close the fold.
the faster we can say goodbye
to the music.
- Copy that. Ensign.
- She was talking to me.
- You don't know that.
I do know that. I actually work here.
This isn't even your department.
You're xenoanthropology.
I was assigned here at your request.
She said you missed me.
Everything's connected to
the deflector.
Ready to go. Nyota.
Deflector aligned
and ready to fire.
On your command. Number One.
It's closing.
Good work. all.
What is it?
It appears to be another energy surge.
Somehow. I don't think we zipped it.
Spock. what happened?
Unable to determine.
Incoming hail from the Cayuga.
When it rains...
Spock. find a way to determine it.
Ensign Uhura.
put Captain Batel through. please.
Captain. can we have
a private conversation?
In a more discreet location?
About our canceled vacation.
Apologies
I appear to be rhyming
And singing
Marie. I'm gonna call you back.
Oh. no. no. you don't
I'm not done yet
Chris. you always do this
You always run away
Oh. sure. I see
Lay all the blame on me
When you're the one
Whose idea of fun is...
What am I saying to you
In front of my crew?
This is a private conversation
A private conversation
About our frustration
This is a private conversation
A private conversation
About our frustration
We must contain it
We must restrain it
I don't want to hurt you. Marie
You mean more and more to me
But when you and I
Don't see eye to eye
A switch inside me flips
And I'm compelled to hide
What just happened?
Why did I admit all that?
I told you. This is a security threat.
But the singing... The...
How did that happen
on the Cayuga. too?
Because the improbability field
is expanding
across the whole subspace
communications network.
To the entire fleet.
Admiral April's last message
confirmed that
the improbability field
has now spread to 12 Federation ships.
He let me know
in a surprisingly beautiful baritone
that he wants us to stop this now.
by the way.
Do we have any idea why
this reality's compelling us
to confess our deepest emotions?
I have a theory.
I think.
since we're in a musical reality.
we're actually following
the rules of musicals.
So. when do characters in musicals
usually begin to sing?
When their emotions are so heightened
that words won't suffice.
This musical reality
wants us to sing about
what's most pressing on our minds.
These emotions
have the power to overwhelm
our capacity for rational thinking.
They also have the potential
to drive us apart.
The subspace fold.
I think we should blow it up.
Use the photon torpedoes
to bring down the curtain on this
for good.
- That has potential.
- Really?
Since we are the focal point
of this subspace fold.
a matter/antimatter blast
might untether the Enterprise.
and reverse the musical reality
for all affected.
But it would be prudent
to test this theory
in a controlled environment.
in case it is more explosive
than intended.
What if we could isolate
and transport...
Subatomic particles from the fold.
Sorry.
I shouldn't have interrupted you.
because you had that thought first.
Locking in on something that small
would require cross-targeting.
It's a two-person job.
Well. luckily you have
two persons right here.
You're refusing an assignment?
This isn't like you. La'An.
That's the problem.
I'm not behaving like myself.
None of us are.
- You're afraid of singing... to James.
- What?
You can stop hiding it.
I see how you act around him.
What do you mean?
How do I act around him?
You don't want me to answer that.
Okay.
Hypothetically. let's say
I have feelings for him.
and those feelings pose
an actual space-time security risk.
I should just tell him.
That's the responsible thing to do.
Before it happens
outside of my control.
I should just suck it up.
stop being a child and just do it.
You've got lots of
Thoughts to wade through
Tangled webs
Of people who will
Complicate your life
And thwart you
These are facts
That I relate to
Pick and choose
The truth that you want to tell
If you're being smart
No broken trust. no drama
You just keep to yourself
Be your own best friend
And confidante
'Cause no one will protect you
When things go wrong
The secrets you keep safe inside
Might keep you awake
And cut like a knife
'Cause the road to ruin
Is paved by intentions of fools
Nice people who
Couldn't keep a secret
No one can keep you small
Be bulletproof and ten feet tall
An island
Population one
No one can hurt you
Or let you down again
The secrets I keep safe inside
A skill I perfected
So I could survive
It worked before
It doesn't serve me anymore
I wish I never learned
How to be
So good at keeping secrets
We should boost the gain
on the targeting scanners.
Way ahead of you.
Do we have a lock on the target?
Sorry. Reflex.
This is your ship.
you give the orders.
Ready on both ends.
Energizing... now.
The molecular imaging scanner
can't focus the signal.
Adding power.
Isolating particles
from the subspace fold.
Got it.
Confirmed.
Lieutenant Spock.
I have the particles.
They're coming your way.
Acknowledged.
Ready to receive.
Transporting subspace particles
to Engineering.
Wow. That was exciting.
I mean. Spock and Uhura
get to blow it up.
which is the real fun part. but...
We make a good pair.
We should team up more often.
Lieutenant. um...
- Jim.
- Jim?
You sound so serious.
I. um...
What was that?
If hitting
just a few subatomic particles
nearly blew up Engineering...
Firing on the field
would be devastating.
As you can see in this simulation.
the explosion would propagate through
the entire
Federation subspace network.
destroying everything.
It would be like soaking
the improbability field in kerosene
and holding a match to it.
Then we need a plan C.
Sir. I'm getting a hail.
Don't answer.
We can't risk spreading this further.
I am triangulating the source.
There appears to be
an incoming warp signal
heading our way fast.
The signal has Klingon encryption.
The last thing anyone wants
is singing Klingons.
Uhura. send a message by proxy
order of Starfleet Command.
Tell them
they must turn around immediately.
They've stopped hailing.
but I'm getting a message back.
The improbability field's
already hit them.
Stand by for playback.
This is General Garkog of
the Imperial Klingon Defense Force.
Your evasion raises much suspicion.
We have located
the abominable source of our dishonor
and will destroy it immediately.
Make no attempt to stop us.
They're going to fire on the fold.
Their ship will be here in two hours.
I've hailed them repeatedly.
They refuse to answer.
If they complete their mission.
everyone affected
by the improbability field
will be destroyed.
So. just the entire Federation
and half the Klingon Empire.
We have to stop them at all costs.
Number One. analysis?
Well. striking them first
would constitute an act of war.
Not much choice here.
I'm afraid.
What if we just find a way
to disable their disruptor cannons?
And their torpedo launchers.
That's a lot to disable
before they get off a shot.
We need a tactical strategy
immediately. La'An?
On it.
And you. You're with me.
Partners again. I like it. Let's go.
Mr. Spock. Uhura.
what are the odds we can shut down
the improbability field
before the Klingons get here?
Not good. At least. according to
the data we have.
Then find new data.
You both need to fix this.
You're applying old rules
to a new reality.
I suggest you find
a different tempo. fast.
Studying the songs themselves.
Brilliant.
Not just the songs.
but the frequencies
the moment a song begins.
If we can isolate a pattern
in the improbability field.
we might learn how to generate
an improbability-breaking event.
Now. how to trigger a song?
Well. per our musical rules.
we just need to wait until someone
feels overwhelming emotion.
You know...
like that.
To our brilliant
friend Christine.
Oh. I feel weird celebrating
with everything going on.
I mean. we can't put our lives on hold
every time the ship's in trouble.
We could. but that wouldn't be fun.
Some of us need fun to deal with
the constant threat of dying.
Point is. we're here to celebrate
your win. so deal with it.
Christine.
Logic would dictate you are toasting
good news regarding your fellowship.
so allow me to...
offer congratulations.
Thank you. Spock.
I am curious
why you chose not to inform me.
Was it an oversight
or was it intentional?
Can we. um...
Can we talk about this later?
I am just curious.
This news really
changes everything
A distant dream becoming real
I convinced myself
It wasn't happening
And now I'm surprised
How good it feels
I worked so hard for this
And now the fellowship
Sees me as one of their own
The sky is the limit
My future is infinite
My possibilities are endless
I'm ready
Drink in every second of the joy
You've earned it. deserve it
Of success arriving overnight
- You've earned it
- But not really
Been working hard a long time
I've been seeing life
Through camera obscura
Now my canvas
Is wide as the open horizon
I worked so hard for this
And now the fellowship
Sees me as one of their own
The sky is the limit
My future is infinite
With possibilities
It's freedom. and I like it
My spark has been ignited
If I need to leave you
I won't fight it
I'm ready
Ready. ready
- I am ready
- Ready. ready. ooh
I'm ready
Ready. ready
I'm ready.
Number One suggested
we concentrate our phasers
on their disruptors
and fore torpedoes.
Aft torpedoes are what
you really have to worry about
when it comes to K't'inga-class ships.
Well. I trust your aim.
So. are you gonna tell me that thing
you wanted to tell me before?
Okay. Uh. I-I need to just say this
before it comes out
in the form of
a 17th-century sea shanty.
I. um...
I know you.
I mean. not you you.
We-Well. I know you now.
but I mean before. in a different...
time. I met another you.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
I-I don't love rules.
but I'm pretty sure
you're about to break a big one.
The other you. he. um...
He saw the real me.
Beyond my name.
beyond all that name stands for.
He'd never even heard it before.
And I. I liked it.
I liked the way he looked at me.
Because through his eyes.
I could finally see the person
I had the potential to be.
And it was someone
who wasn't burdened by...
Tragedy and darkness.
Someone who could find hope
and live in that hope.
Someone free. free to feel and...
Take chances. and. um...
And make connections.
But then. uh...
He was gone. and... with him.
that version of myself was gone. too.
And that's...
That was what I wanted to say.
Am I anything like the other me?
No.
And... And yes.
I like how you look at me. too.
In what way?
Like you really see me.
I'd be lying if I said
I didn't feel the connection. too.
When you first called me...
I felt like I knew you.
But I'm not that James Kirk.
Of course.
It was inappropriate. and I am...
No. La'An. you don't understand. My...
My life is complicated.
Not time-travel complicated.
but I'm in a relationship.
A sometimes relationship.
and right now is one of those times
in a very real way.
- My God. if I'd have known. I...
- How could you have?
I actually think you'd like Carol.
You're both
dedicated to your jobs intensely.
She's a scientist on Starbase 1.
I tend not to stay in the same place
for very long. which is...
a growing problem. because Carol is...
pregnant.
Oh. um...
Wow.
Here you are.
I have been analyzing
the data we gathered.
Great. Uh. let me help.
Looking for a pattern.
Only...
There is none.
I... didn't expect Christine
to be so definitive
about ending our arrangement.
Uh... relationships
can be difficult. Spock.
And you're Vulcan.
But I am also human.
I feel things differently.
Bigger.
I see her logic. and yet...
I am hurt.
I am left behind.
This news really
changes everything
I can't believe how wrong I've been
Convinced myself
We shared the same feelings
I won't make that mistake again
She's happy and carefree
The opposite of me
I can do the calculus
For her I set aside
My need to analyze
Now I'm wrecked
And searching for why
I'm the ex
I've got no one but myself to blame
I've betrayed my core philosophy
Unbending reason
Must be my true north
Lest I drown in this sea of pain
I'm so dysfunctional
Weak and emotional
Feelings I just can't contain
Escaping this misery
You're breaking free
Not a possibility
I solved for Y in my computation
But missed vital information
The variable so devastating
I'm the X
I'm the X.
I'm sorry.
A pattern.
I have to find a pattern.
A pattern repeating
I find myself here all alone
I know
I'll pick up the pieces
Repair what is broken alone
I know
Memories etched in my mind
Of Mom and Dad
A cool big brother I would idolize
So full of laughter
And I could trust in the four of us
They flew away
Nothing to indicate calamity
All so young and alive
Oh
They ruptured into
A million shards of light
And none of them would survive
How come everywhere that I go
I'm solo?
Am I at my best unaccompanied?
My whole life has been
"Fix this" and "save you"
I'll light the path
And keep us connected
My fabric is woven
With love and loss
I was just a cadet when we met
Hemmer's belief in me
Changed my life
I found my place
And said goodbye
I absorb all the pain
Mmm
I hear everyone's voice
Calling my name
Building systems
I strengthen ties that bind
So no one has to be alone
How come everywhere that I go
I'm solo?
Am I at my best unaccompanied?
My whole life has been
"Fix this" and "save you"
I'll light the path
And keep us connected
The patterns repeating
Guiding and teaching me
I know
Listen for signals
I'm here
You are reaching me
Come home
Everywhere I go
I'm good with solo
At my best. I have everything I need
My whole life has been
"Fix this" and "save you"
That's what I do
I keep us connected
Look. It's a pattern.
Every time someone sings.
the state of quantum improbability
in the field spikes.
It's almost imperceptible.
but it's there.
So. I ran the simulations...
...and if we can get this spike
to 344 giga electronvolts...
It would shatter the field.
You found
the improbability-breaking event.
Great. So how do we make
this event happen?
Because our sensors just clocked
two more K't'inga battle cruisers
headed this direction.
Well. so far.
we've only witnessed people
being torn apart by this event.
But song can also be communal.
People worship with song.
Sailors use song
to help them row together.
People celebrate with song.
When I sang with Christine
in the port galley.
A spike of 40 electronvolts.
And that was just a solo
with backup vocals.
Maybe four voices. max.
So we need to do that again...
...but with more.
A lot more.
You mean like an ensemble number.
or...
Not just an ensemble number.
A grand finale.
We need melodies and harmonies
with tone ratios that achieve
both algorithmic
and logarithmic balance
on a mass scale.
What I'm saying is...
The whole crew needs to sing together.
Our challenge is
how to inspire 200 crew members
to spontaneously sing
in thematic unison.
A song cannot be triggered
without an emotional purpose.
Well. that sounds to me like a job
for a communications officer.
I can't possibly inspire
the entire ship to sing.
Oh. yes. you can.
You see the connections between us
when all we see are...
The empty spaces.
Help them to feel
the way they need to to sing.
Attention all crew.
this is your captain.
I know our situation
has been challenging.
and we might not all have been
acting like a...
Well. like a crew.
But we'll get through this. together.
by following one voice...
The voice of the Enterprise.
Ensign Uhura?
Hi... everyone.
Uh. you might not all know me.
but I know you.
So. allow me to introduce myself.
Ensign Nyota Uhura.
your communications officer.
I used to think of myself
as always alone.
but not on this ship.
Because each of us.
we're connected as a crew.
Do you know the odds
of all of us being here
on the Enterprise at this time?
It's improbable.
and yet here we are.
together. all of us.
This is where it all leads
The Enterprise
Is it my destiny
To save us all?
No.
It's myjob to disrupt the chaos
Find a purpose for us all
We're all rushing around
We're confused and upended
Let's refocus now
Our bond is imperative
Let's bring our collective together
As we fight for our lives
Uhura. I really needed to hear that
Our security's
Only as strong as our unity
When I scan the universe
It reveals truth and gives meaning
It's what I'm meant to do
The danger's not over yet
When we gain control again
I confess I'll miss the singing
Won't miss singing
Now let's bring this thing down
We know our purpose is
To protect the mission
Our directive
'Cause we work better all together
We overcome
Our obstacles as one
Keep going!
I have to give credit when due
And if I make captain
It'll be thanks to all of you
And I don't take for granted
My role to command
I can't believe how much
I'll miss this crew
The starship Enterprise
Feels electrified
I'm so proud to be your captain
Now let's take this thing down
Down
We know our purpose is
To protect the mission
Our directive
'Cause we work better all together
We overcome
Our obstacles as one
I look around and everyone I see
The pinnacle of guts and resiliency
Yes. threats are nothing new to us
It takes monumental strength
And trust
We got lost and disconnected
Distracted. undefended
Uhura. you saved us
More singing. more voices
Hail the Klingons. Uhura
Why have you... Ugh!
Why you only calling us
When you got your dramas?
One of these days
We'll repay you. we'll slay you
Gonna draw your last breath
At the end of our mek'leths
Your eternal torture
Is every Klingon's dream
You know what I mean?
Make your blood scream!
We know our purpose
- Is
- We know our purpose
To protect the mission
Our prime directive
Not exactly.
Will this work? Who can say?
We're gonna sing it anyway
Our voices will rise
Through space and through time
We're the unbreakable. unshakable
Improbable. unstoppable
Sensational. ovational
We're boldly explorational
Crew of the Enterprise!
- We did it!
- Yes! Come on.
Nyota.
Hail the Klingons.
I think we might have to
mend some fences.
Hey. how are you?
I told Kirk the truth.
- How'd it go?
- Honestly...
Not great. I. uh...
It was really hard. And it hurt.
It usually does.
I'm glad I took that chance.
Maybe. um...
Maybe I could be someone
who takes chances more often.
You know.
I don't need a whole to-do.
Just relax. Enjoy it.
I promise you. even Julia Child's
boeuf bourguignon itself
will not make me forget
that you sang about lying to me.
Why didn't you just tell me
you hate the idea of Crivo?
I don't hate the idea.
Okay. yes.
it sounded like my nightmare.
I just pictured something quieter.
Camping somewhere.
Chris. this isn't gonna work
if you're not more comfortable
being honest with me.
Even about something
as small as a vacation.
You got to trust me more than that.
You got to trust us.
I know. You're right.
Well. I have good news and bad news.
We have more time to plan
our compromised trip.
I just got put on
a priority one mission.
Hmm.
Now. how do I know
you're not the one making excuses now?
Well...
When I'm back.
we'll go somewhere we both want to go.
But no camping.
unless it comes with room service.
Deal.
Communications Officer's Log.
supplemental.
I am happy to report that
all Federation vessels
have checked in and are
behaving normally once again.
As for the Klingons.
Lieutenant Spock engaged
in successful diplomacy
over some bloodwine.
Otherwise. it's back to business
as usual around here.
U.S.S. Nimerfro.
this is Enterprise
acknowledging receipt
of your transmission.
- You fly safe out there.
- Acknowledged. Enterprise.
Uhura.
it occurs to me that we'd be served by
sharing our findings
with non-Federation ships. too.
See who's nearby and open a channel.
Copy that. sir. I'll scan the area.
Sorry. Earworm.
English - SDH